Mss.Ms.Coll.104
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Correspondence-Hare Family, 1724-1965
  - Case of Toland and Sprague, 1824; No. 40
    Papers relating to Henry Toland's Claim against Horatio Sprague on shipment on ship William Penn.
  - Clark (son) to Mrs. Hare, 1825 June 17; No. 41
    Child's letter to Mother while at Grandmother's. (Note from Grandmother telling that Clark was stung by a bee.)
  - Josiah & Sarah Bunting to James Moore, 1826 November 3; No. 42
    James Moore's deed to property on Bonsall Street, Philadelphia.
  - William Hooper's commencement oration, 1829 June 24; No. 43
    Commencement oration delivered at Chapel Hill by William Hooper, A.M. on "The Prospects of Our Common Country".
  - Horace Binney to Esther Cox Binney, 1829 July 8; No. 44
  - Mary B. Wallace to Esther C. Binney, 1829 July 22; No. 45
    Telling about children, Elizabeth and Susan and other family news.
  - Clark Hare (Grandson) to Mrs. Lydia Clark, 1829 August 23; No. 46
    Describing visit to New York, Albany and Saratoga.
  - Will of Lydia Clark, 1830 April 15; No. 47
  - Mary T. Sargeant to Esther C. Binney, 1830 November 18; No. 48
    Sympathy letter on sister's death.
  - University of Pennsylvania to Dr. Robert Hare, 1831; No. 49
    University of Pennsylvania reports on John I. Hare.
  - University of Pennsylvania to Dr. Robert Hare, 1831-1832; No. 50
    University of Pennsylvania reports on Clark Hare.
  - Horace Binney (father) to Esther Cox Binney, 1832 January 25; No. 51
    Told of visiting President Jackson and talk about family to daughter
  - Horace Binney to Esther Cox Binney, 1832 February 10; No. 52
    Fatherly advise on 15th birthday and promise of a watch. Enclosed check to deposit for collection.
  - Horace Binney to Esther Cox Binney, 1833 January 27; No. 53
    On benefiting the mind.
  - Maria E.E. Bell to Miss Binney, 1833 February 12; No. 54
    Travels over England, Scotland, France and Italy, and description of towns and sights (particularly in Rome).
  - Clark Hare to "Sir", 1833 March 7; No. 55
    On bituminous coal.
  - Horace Binney to Esther Cox Binney, 1833 April 29; No. 56
    Against medicine, but prescribes exercise, air, temperance and cheerfulness.
  - Horace Binney to Esther Cox Binney, 1833 August 21; No. 57
    Giving hints and cautions in regard to your observations in New York and advice on respect to persons your senior.
  - William Bell to Miss Binney, 1833 October 11; No. 58
    Advising of the deliverance of a "dressing case."
  - Horace Binney to Esther Cox Binney, 1833 December 2; No. 59
    Explaining being a new member of the House, and discussing the power of using a faculty and improving it by use.
  - Mary Sargent to Esther Cox Binney, 1834 September 11; No. 60
    Account of travels across Lake Winnipesaukee and White Mountains, New Hampshire.
  - Horace Binney to Miss Binney, 1834 December 8; No. 61
    Rambling letter of advice.
  - Horace Binney to Miss Binney, 1835 January 19; No. 62
    Will not consent to your taking a journey to Meadville.
  - Horace Binney to Miss Binney, 1835 February 8; No. 63
    On laziness and making the best of the present. In which he quotes "I feel as if, I should begin a new life, when I cast off the slough of this miserable crawling life in Congress."
  - Eliza S_____ ? to Mrs. Hare, 1839 March 20; No. 64
    (part of a letter)
  - Oliver Kane to Clark Hare, 1839 June 18; No. 65
    In reference to Totten and Crossfield lands which belonged to estate of late Mr. Clark.
  - Julia Powel to Harrison Hare, 1840 April 2; No. 66
    Something about getting Baring out of the country and advising you not to see him and stop making demands on him.
  - William Binney (brother) to Esther C. Binney, 1840 April 22; No. 67
    Idle talk and secrets.
  - Lill to Miss Binney, 1841 May 5; No. 68
    Social visits and general chatter.
  - William (brother) to Esther Binney, 1841 January 6; No. 69
    How Christmas was spent. Deaths of Mr. Ralston and Mr. Hillhouse (poet).
  - Lill (sister) to Miss Esther Binney, 1841 March 27; No. 70
    Mama might not get to Bordentown on Monday. Mrs. Dunlap's death. Visits.
  - William (brother) to Miss Esther Binney, 1841 July 28; No. 71
    Rambling letter to sister. Reading interesting history, Ferdinand and Isabella.
  - Lill (sister) to Miss Esther Binney, 1842 August 3; No. 72
    Papa in New York on Stevens' business. Willie coming home on vacation. Enjoyed Anna T's visit. Now extraordinary sponge cake baker.
  - Horace Binney to Esther C. Hare, 1842 December 3; No. 73
    Sending check for $100 for present family expenses and will send $500 in January and the same in July.
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania to Joseph B. Townsend and William Goocher, 1843 February 10; No. 74
    Subpoena - in case of John Hare Powel and John Clayton, Jr.
  - Mother Hare to Mrs. J.I. Clark Hare, 1843 July 30; No. 75
    General home news.
  - Mr. Hare (brother) to Clark Hare, 1843 November 23; No. 76
    Account of passage to England and landing.
  - Horace Binney to Mrs. E.C. Hare, 1844 February 2; No. 77
    Sitting in Supreme Court on Girard case.
  - Mother Binney to Esther C. Hare, 1844 July 23; No. 78
  - Horace Binney to Esther, 1844 December 6; No. 79
    Two notes from Father. Thank you for flowers.
  - Horace Binney to Mrs. E.C. Hare, 1845 July 21; No. 80
  - ________ to ________, 1837; No. 80a
  - E.M. Fischer to Horace Binney, 1840 December 24; No. 80b
    Christmas greetings on stationery with lace boarder.
  - Mother to Mrs. J.I. Clark Hare, 1845 August 3; No. 81
    News of your son, Binney, who is staying with Grandparents.
  - Daniel Webster to a friend, 1846 May 3; No. 82
    A newspaper copy of a letter written about his early life and his father.
  - Mother to Mrs. J.I.C. Hare, 1846 August 1; No. 83
    Home and family news.
  - Horace Binney to Mrs. Esther C. Hare, 1846 August 12; No. 84
    Pleading that you "come home".
  - Horace Binney to Mrs. Esther C. Hare, 1846 August 19; No. 85
    Will come for the "Boy" Monday.
  - Horace Binney to Mrs. Clark Hare, 1846 August 25; No. 86
    Arrived in perfect safety with the "Boy".
  - Clark Hare to Horace Binney, 1846 November 4; No. 87
    Copy of opinion of Horace Binney's on the sums of money due widow of Robert Hare, Clair de Pestre Hare.
  - Greene & Co. to Mrs. Clara de Pestre Hare, 1847 January 21; No. 88
  - Horace Binney to Esther, 1847 February 2; No. 89
    No one can go, so make your arrangements accordingly.
  - Horace Binney to Mrs. E.C. Hare, 1847 March 29; No. 90
    Enclosed second bill of exchange for 3200 francs. News of the "boy" (Horace Binney Hare).
  - Horace Binney Hare to Esther Hare, 1847; No. 91
    Child's scribbling.
  - Horace Binney to Mrs. Hare, 1847 May 29; No. 92
    Questions and answers to son and news of him. Mother and your son to go to Hoboken.
  - Esther to Horace Binney, 1847 June 3; No. 93
    Account of birth of Elizabeth's son (your grandson).
  - Horace Binney to J.I.C. Hare, 1847 June 10; No. 94
    Additional $500 for trip to join your wife.
  - Horace Binney to Mrs. Esther Hare, 1847 June 13; No. 95
    Anxiety on Elizabeth's health. Quarrel with Bishop of New Jersey diocese. News of your son and husband.
  - Robert Hare to Richard Phillips, 1847 June 26; No. 96
    Introducing son, J.I. Clark Hare.
  - Esther to Horace Binney, 1847 July 10; No. 97
    Clark's arrival a surprise. Gratitude for your assistance. Discussing Bishop in Burlington (dishonest acts).
  - Horace Binney to Mrs. Esther C. Hare, 1847 July 29; No. 98
    News of your "boy".
  - Robert Hare to Mme. Clara de Pestre, 1848; No. 99
  - Euphrosina to Mrs. Clark Hare, 1848 January 12; No. 100
    Activities in Paris and general news.
  - Anne Ives to Horace Binney Hare, 1848 June 20; No. 101
    Sending book and cake.
  - Horace Binney to Esther Hare, 1848 July 26; No. 102
    Whether or not they can proceed to Newport. On "bringing up" the boy.
  - Mother to Esther Hare, 1848 July 30; No. 103
  - Mother to Esther Hare, 1849 June 26; No. 104
    Arrived home tired, dirty and without carpet bag. Home and family news. Carpet bag arrived.
  - Horace Binney to Esther Hare, 1849 July 3; No. 105
    Richard, Elizabeth and children have left for Newport. Could not take journey to Fort Hamilton in heat by train and steamboat. General news.
  - Horace Binney to Esther Hare, 1849 July 7; No. 106
    May come with Susan to Fort Hamilton since there is an earlier boat. Talk on dying, Cholera and boy's diet.
  - Horace Binney to Esther Hare, 1849 August 1; No. 107
    Comments and advice about boy's accident. Horace's attack of rheumatism and method of gaining strength.
  - Horace Binney to Clark, 1849 August 30; No. 108
    Friend, Chauncey of Burlington, died. Cholera has disappeared from city. Town now filled with businessmen from West.
  - Horace Binney to Esther Hare, 1849 September 9; No. 109
    Joking about remembering your house and acquaintances after an absence of six months.
  - Mother to Mrs. Clark Hare, 1849 September 25; No. 110
    About illness, table cover, Lizzie to live nearby and other family news.
  - A.A. Ives to Mrs. J.I.C. Hare, 1850 January 28; No. 111
    General chatter on health, reading, and author, Miss Bremer.
  - Mother to Esther Hare, 1850 February 10; No. 112
    Birthday greetings.
  - Horace Binney to Esther Hare, 1850 June 17; No. 113
    Family news and health. Comparing women to wind and talking of Irishmen.
  - E.B.M. (sister) to Esther Hare, 1850 June 21; No. 114
    Home, family and town news.
  - Horace Binney Jr. to Clark Hare, 1850 July 2; No. 115
    Received and deposited $520 to your credit. Mentions court cases, Horace's travels, politics and Police Bell. Willie had chicken pox.
  - Horace Binney to Mrs. Esther C. Hare, 1850 July 16; No. 116
    Family and home news. Note to Horace (grandson).
  - Horace Binney to J.I. Clark Hare, 1850 August 7; No. 117
    Annoyed with heat and sprained ankle, but hopes in a few days to go North with Horace. Review on his reading.
  - J.P. Hutchinson to Clark Hare, 1850 November 12; No. 118
    In reference to account of Mrs. Clara Hare.
  - Horace Binney to Mrs. Clark Hare, 1850 December 24; No. 119
    Give the boy his Wilde-beast.
  - A.A. Ives to Mrs. J.I. Clark Hare, 1851 March 24; No. 120
    Health, Horace and general chat.
  - Horace Binney to Esther C. Hare, 1851 July 10; No. 121
    Advice on walking and request you write larger and pay postage.
  - Horace Binney to Mrs. Hare, 1851 July 23; No. 122
    News of home, townsfolk and family. Advice on raising Horace and writing letters.
  - Anne A. Ives to Mrs. Hare, 1851 July 31; No. 123
    Invitation to visit. Saw your Mother in Newport.
  - Mother to Mrs. J.I. Clark Hare, 1851 August 1; No. 124
    Head still "roars". Lizzie's eyes no better. Expecting Father and Susie. News of family and friends.
  - Horace Binney to Esther C. Hare, 1851 August 8; No. 125
    Account of bad trip in fog to Newport from New York by steamer, with steam whistle shrieking and joking in comparison to choir at Christ Church. (two ships disabled in fog.)
  - Anne A. Ives to Mrs. J.I. Clark Hare, 1851 August 15; No. 126
    Invitation to visit.
  - Horace Binney to Esther C. Hare, 1851 August 28; No. 127
    Clark has left for New Rochelle. A rather humorous portion of the letter with such things as, try moistening the letter instead of the stamp, and wants to see "Boy, but is glad his front teeth have had time to grow," and "the steel pen is a villainous invention". Then saddened by visit to Boston which has changed so in 50 years.
  - S.E. Hare to J.I. Clark Hare, 1851 October 21; No. 128
    In reference to an opinion requested on settlement of Mother's estate.
  - ________ to J.I. Clark Hare, 1852; No. 129
    Papers relative to the estate of Martha Hare.
  - Mother to Esther, 1853 September 30; No. 130
    Clark arrived. Home news of housecleaning, preserving, etc.
  - Classical Institute to Horace B. Hare, 1853 December 24; No. 131
    School report. (No. 1 in class of 11)
  - Classical Institute to Horace B. Hare, 1854 January 14; No. 132
    School report.
  - Classical Institute to Horace B. Hare, 1854 January 21; No. 133
  - Newspaper - New York Herald, 1854 April 5; No. 134
    Correspondence of Emperor of Russia to England on Turkey. (Crimean War)
  - Horace Binney to Horace Binney Hare, 1854 July 4; No. 135
    Grandpa's letter telling of Uncle Horace's visit to the opening of the Court and meeting with the Lord Mayor at Mansion House.
  - Horace Binney to Mrs. E.C. Hare, 1854 July 7; No. 136
  - Thomas Donaldson to Dr. Robert Hare, 1854 October 12; No. 137
    Receipt for $4000 for sale of furniture, stock, etc. of National Hotel for Meacham and Hayward from George Lane.
  - Newspaper - New York Daily Tribune, 1854 November 4; No. 138
    On the state of Europe. (Crimean War)
  - Horace Binney Hare to ________, 1854 November 17; No. 139
    Composition on squirrels in Washington Square.
  - F.H. Smith to Professor Hare, 1855 July 3; No. 140
    On Spiritualism. Wants to know which Francis Hopkinson was communicated with, and an invitation to lecture.
  - Opinion by J. Hare in Hammet vs. Harrison, 1852 March 27; No. 140a
  - N.P. Tallmadge to the editors, 1853 May 4; No. 140b
    Upholding belief in spiritualism.
  - Newspaper article, 1854; No. 140c
    On Sharon Springs, New York.
  - Map of City of Philadelphia, 1854; No. 140d
    May of City of Philadelphia according to Act of 1854. (Boundaries of Wards)
  - Newspaper article by Robert Clough, 1855 October 20; No. 140e
    "Extraordinary Case of Imposture" - by Robert Clough, Superintendent of Police, Liverpool.
  - Thomas Wetherill, Odenheimer & Cook, S. Baldwin & Co. to Judges of the District Court, 1856 April 4; No. 141
    Letter of recommendation for C.D. Lybradth.
  - Horace Binney to Clark Hare, 1856 July 10; No. 142
    General news.
  - Esther to Mrs. Binney, 1857 January 22; No. 143
    Sympathy letter on loss of friend, and birthday greetings.
  - Classical Institute to H.B. Hare, 1857 April 4; No. 144
    School report card (1 in class of 16)
  - Horace Binney Hare to Mrs. J.I. Clark Hare, 1857 April 11; No. 145
    Went to Staten Island yesterday.
  - Horace Binney Hare to Mrs. J.I. Clark Hare, 1857 April 14; No. 146
    Arrived safely last night.
  - Horace Binney Hare to Mrs. J.I. Clark Hare, 1857 April 18; No. 147
    At school, staying at Helen G's, New York.
  - ________ to Clark, 1857 July 17; No. 148
    (Part of a letter) Harvesting crops - wheat and potatoes. About ships. (Very hard to read)
  - Obituary of George Harrison Hare, 1857 July 24; No. 149
    Obituary notices of George Harrison Hare, son of Dr. Robert Hare. (From the Intelligence)
  - Mother to Esther, 1858 February 10; No. 150
  - Binney & Hare, Printers, 1858 April; No. 151
    Advertisement.
  - Binney & Hare, Printers, 1858; No. 152
  - Binney & Hare, Printers to Mrs. E.C. Hare, 1859; No. 153
    Port wine labels and admission tickets to Museum.
  - Binney & Hare, Printers to Mrs. E.C. Hare, 1859; No. 154
    Currant Jelly labels.
  - Binney & Hare, Printers to Mrs. E.C. Hare, 1859; No. 155
    Season ticket to the Museum.
  - Binney & Hare Printers, 1859; No. 156
    Advertising printing.
  - Maria Fisher to Emily Beale, 1859; No. 157
    Acceptance to spend the day on Saturday.
  - Collegiate & Commercial Academy to H.B. Hare, 1859 January 7; No. 158
    Report Card.
  - Binney & Hare Printers, 1859 April; No. 159
    Printing advertisements.
  - Horace Binney Hare to Mamma, 1859 July 12; No. 160
    Account of trip to Eastport and then will on to Dorchester. (And a note from Clark).
  - Newspaper article, 1857 June 15; No. 160a
    German Musical Jubilee
  - Horace Binney Hare to Mrs. Clark Hare, 1859 July 17; No. 161
    Telling of trip and talk with private who fought all through Crimean War. Seasickness and bedbugs.
  - C.H. to Mrs. Clark Hare, 1859 August 5; No. 162
    All about trip. Leaving for home, but Horace anxious to prolong trip, while Clark wants to get home.
  - ________ to ________, 1859 October 31; No. 163
    About Charley (?)
  - Collegiate and Commercial Academy to H.B. Hare, 1860 January 21; No. 164
  - C.H. to Mrs. Clark Hare, 1860 May 5; No. 165
    Arrived, looking for a place for the summer.
  - Philadelphia, 1860 July; No. 166
    Japanese cards, etc.
  - Horace Binney Hare to Mrs. Hare, 1860 September 2; No. 167
    Arrived, joined Uncle Horace and John and furnished rooms. Took exams last week. Request for little more money, books, towels, sheets, dusters, and winter drawers.
  - Horace Binney Hare to Mrs. J.I. Clark Hare, 1860 September 9; No. 168
    About "sock" in place of bandage on ankle. Ordered black frock coat and shoes, and would like to get suit. Weather, his schedule, request for money, towels, dusters, and engravings.
  - Horace Binney Hare to Mrs. Hare, 1860 September 16; No. 169
    Has rheumatism and wants liniment and medicine. Tells about Sophomores smashing windows of Freshmen, his friends, "Goote's History of Greece", and requests red curtains (the thing there). Account of expenditures.
  - Horace Binney Hare to Mrs. Hare, 1860 September 23; No. 170
    All about college. Umbrella stolen. Was invited to tea at Sallie Dana's but declined because of rheumatism which is now better. Request for books and pantaloons.
  - Horace Binney Hare to J.I. Clark Hare, 1860 September 30; No. 171
    One month at college has been very pleasant. Doctor making support for foot. Getting clothes. Visited Mrs. Dana. Met friend from Sidney, Cape Breton, who he had gone fossil hunting with. (Note to Mamma).
  - H.B. Hare to Mrs. Hare, 1860 October 7; No. 172
    Request for pens, carpet blower holder, nailbrush, olein and toothbrushes. Instructions on trains and boats in coming up. Marks. Saw Anna Lea. Cambridge very muddy. Account of expenses.
  - H.B. Hare to Judge Hare, 1860 October 9; No. 173
    Elected a member of boat club and request for permission to join.
  - Newspaper - The New York Times, 1860 October 13; No. 174
    "The Prince in the Metropolis" (Prince of Wales)
  - Horace Binney Hare to Mrs. Hare, 1860 October 14; No. 175
    Prince to be there. News of the college. Went to Theatre to see "Lalla Rookh". Looking forward to your visit at end of week.
  - Horace Binney Hare to J.I. Clark Hare, 1860 October 15; No. 176
    Information on the boat club.
  - Horace Binney Hare to Mrs. Hare, 1860 October 28; No. 177
    About clothes, skating reel and is sending book (a sermon by Dr. Huntingdon). Freshman caps.
  - Horace Binney Hare to J.I. Clark Hare, 1860 November 4; No. 178
    About clothes to be ordered and college marks.
  - Horace Binney Hare to Mrs. Hare, 1860 November 11; No. 179
    Would like India rubber boots. Ordered clothes. Met Mr. Perly. Museum of Professor Agassi to be "consecrated". Saw Horace Sargent (cousin)and is invited to dinner. Expects to go to Providence for Thanksgiving. Someone turned off gas 2 nights and school was dismissed early.
  - Horace Binney Hare to Mrs. Robert Hare, 1860 November 17; No. 180
    General news of college life.
  - Newspaper articles, 1860; No. 180a
    "Secession".
  - Horace Binney Hare to Mrs. Hare, 1860 November 18; No. 181
    Received "box". Went to dinner at cousin Horace Sargent's. Advises the need of rubber boots.
  - Horace Binney Hare to Mrs. Hare, 1860 November 25; No. 182
    Uncle Willy visited. Couldn't accept invitation for Thanksgiving with Eustis' because already accepted one for Providence with Uncle Willy. Description of "row" at school.
  - Mother to Horace Binney Hare, 1860 December 3; No. 183
    Demanding you write your grandfather.
  - Horace B. Hare to Mrs. Hare, 1860 December 3; No. 184
    Account of Thanksgiving (4 turkeys and pheasants and ducks).
  - Horace Binney to Horace Binney Hare, 1860 December 8; No. 185
    How to use the word "fellow". Comments on Sophmores after hearing of "row" at college.
  - Horace Binney Hare to Judge Hare, 1860 December 9; No. 186
    Request for money for clothes, and for skates. Would like a pair of thin soled shoes for dancing. Account of expenses.
  - Horace Binney Hare to Mrs. Hare, 1860 December 16; No. 187
    Sending photographs. Purchased skates and enjoyed skating. Comments on the "sociables". Feels bad about not being home for Christmas. About studies and temperatures for week.
  - Horace Binney Hare to Mrs. Hare, 1860 December 23; No. 188
    To give "spread" for Christmas Eve. Will go to Mrs. Swett's for Christmas dinner. Weather and temperatures for week. Politics - President Buchanan. Sociables pleasant.
  - E.M. Fisher to Miss Binney, 1860 December 24; No. 189
    Christmas gift to carry bouquets and invitation for tomorrow evening's music.
  - Horace Binney Hare to Mrs. Hare, 1860 December 30; No. 190
    "Spread" went off very well. Spent Christmas at Mrs. Swett's. Comments on the Dana's. Going to dance New Year's eve. Uncle Horace sent barrel of apples. Temperatures for week.
  - Horace Binney Hare to Judge Hare, 1861 January 6; No. 191
    Plans for coming home. Snow and avalanches. Temperatures for week.
  - Horace Binney Hare to J.I.C. Hare, 1861 January 7; No. 192
    Account of Mrs. Baker's bill for room and board.
  - J. Forsythe Meigs to "Dear Sir", 1861 February 19; No. 193
    About "letter" or "lesson" (?)
  - George Gibbs to "Clarke", 1861 April 12; No. 194
    Employed as geologist on North Western Boundary Survey. Description of "Pikes" (name for Western human species). Washington in fear of attack. Comments on Davis, the federal government, and all the agitation at this time.
  - Receiver of taxes to Robert Hare, 1861 April 13; No. 195
    Tax bill for 1861. (properties on Market and Chestnut Sts.)
  - ________ Dix to Clark Hare, 1861 April 23; No. 196
    Receipt for "Intelligence", and letters referring to Dr. R. Hare.
  - R.H. Hall to S.M. Felton, 1861 April 30; No. 197
    Telegram - requesting Judge Hare to furnish letters to Secretary of War by Rush Plumly.
  - Newspaper article, 1861 May 7; No. 198
    Senator Bayard and poem on same.
  - Horace Binney to H.B. Hare, 1861 June 21; No. 199
    Account of his "patriotic duties" love life and friends.
  - Captain Charles Smith to J.I. Clark Hare, 1861 July 2; No. 200
    Notice to parade on 4th of July.
  - Citizens of the City of Philadelphia to the President of the United States, 1861 April 15; No. 200a
    Printed notice - declaring loyalty to government of the United States.
  - N.P. Tillinghast to Emily P. Beale, 1861 August 1; No. 201
    Advice on "trying". Thanks for cushion cover. (And a letter dated July 19, 1861 - sending watch which belonged to your Grandmother and hoping you "strive to be like her")
  - Miss Dix to J.I. Clark Hare, 1861 September 13; No. 202
    A letter from R.H. Hare to Miss Dix and forwarded for Esther with comment "I can't imagine why Robert wrote me such a letter". (Something about property).
  - C.C. Felton to J.I.C. Hare, 1861 October 4; No. 203
    On withdrawing Horace from Harvard.
  - William T. Coleman & Co. to Mr. H.B. Hare, 1861 December 5; No. 204
    Receipt for passage from New York to San Francisco.
  - Horace Binney Hare to Mrs. Hare, 1861 December 8; No. 205
    Expect to leave tomorrow.
  - Horace Binney Hare to Judge Hare, 1861 December 8; No. 206
    Leaving on boat. Has made friends of crew. Sending this by pilot. So far all is well.
  - Horace Binney Hare to Judge Hare, 1862 March; No. 207
    Diary on board, around Cape Horn, from December to March. Sent from San Francisco.
  - Horace Binney Hare to Judge Hare, 1862 March 23; No. 208
    Have enjoyed 4 month voyage, but suffering from headaches. Does not know whom to present letter of introduction. Anxious to find out what army has done. Very friendly with two Yale fellows, Shearer and Sill. Description of arrival in San Francisco.